Matthias Mullie

Full-stack developer

Lijsterstraat 7 8550 Zwevegem, BE +32 472 42 89 94 matthias@mullie.eu



I'm a senior software engineer with an appetite for complex problems. I'm easy going & take responsibility for my work. Most of my expertise is with **PHP**, **Python**, **MySQL**, **JavaScript & related tech**.

I care about code architecture. I love hard challenges, clean code & learning new things. Bonus points for open source projects. I play soccer & like to travel.

Experience

Wikimedia Foundation

San Francisco, USA (remote) 2012 – present

Software engineer

Helped build (cross-wiki) notifications & discussion board. Focused on:

- performance & scaling (e.g. reduced board load time by 3/4)
 storage & architecture (e.g. built transactional cache layer)
- new features like (elastic) search, import/export, permissions (auch!), config, spam/abuse prevention, ...

Wijs

Ghent, BE 2008 – 2012

Lead developer

I lead a 6-person team (half devs) to coordinate client projects. Architected & implemented a wide variety of projects: marketing websites,

e-commerce, ERP integrations, (small) social platforms, ...

Blade fx

Kuurne, BE 2008

Web developer

I sliced up designs & implemented the websites with the company's proprietary ASP framework.

Open source

E Cauditor.org

PHP code analyzer

Set up this AWS-hosted SaaS to extract/visualize metrics for PHP projects. Link GitHub repos & send to 2 SQS queues (1 priority for last commit, other for history) where metrics are generated and submitted back to website. Site is Python, analyzer is PHP (and open source)

Marga Scrapbook.cash

Transactional cache

I implemented a Memcached-like API for multiple cache backends, with stampede protection & transactions(!) etc. on top.

Minifier.org
JS & CSS minifier

How did a few regular expressions for a CMS grow into this thing with 100k+ installs? I'm still convinced these regexes beat an AST approach!

Fork-CMS.com

Content Management System

Grew Fork CMS to 4k+ installs/month & lead its technical direction. Built a lot of the infrastructure: theming, i18n, search, module & theme installers. ...

Certification

Sun

Certified MySQL 5.0 Developer

2010

Zend Certified Engineer PHP 5 & PHP 5.3 2010

CompTIA

Project+ Certified

2011

Education

Katho Bachelor in Applied Computer Science

Kortrijk, BE 2004 – 2011 ASP.NET, Java, Oracle DB, HTML, CSS, XML, Networking, OOP, ...

VDAB PHP developer

Wevelgem, BE 2007 – 2008 PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, XML

Sint-Amandscollege IT Management

Kortrijk, BE 2002 – 2004 ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, Networking

Spes Nostra Institute
Heule, BE
1998 – 2002

Latin-Math
Math and stuff